for for for me it was like the it was it
was almost like a um it was attention I
mean ultimately I mean I didn't get
attention at home because I had no
father I had no structural father at all
and then my mother was barely there from
time to time when she was there you know
what I mean because of her disease um so
she was there uh my siblings they would
pop in once in a blue moon so I mean it
was basically the neighborhood kids
growing up and the man across the street
they used to sexually abuse me I mean
and it went off for years you know what
I'm saying and how what made me feel was
I felt I felt love like that you know I
didn't know if that was right or wrong I
didn't know back then you know I was I
was a young I was a young boy but I'm
saying like that's that's you know
looking back on it like when I was when
I was in my teens I used to think like
man I can't believe people do that like
you know I was I was I was I had so much
hatred so much anger um just I mean I
was full of just malice man straight up
malice and that's why a lot of the
things were happening in my life were
problems I was creating problems for
myself because I had so much built in me
against this man and I never could
forgive him for years for years I
couldn't forgive him in fact I wanted
death on him and uh that's how bad it
was it was just eating me alive you know
and and and in fact it turned me you
doing drugs and drinking and being
around you know that kind of life you
know so I mean yeah it made it made it
made a a mess out of things it made an
absolute mess side of things mhm when
did you realize that you know the
situation that happened to you wasn't
your fault oh man I would say right
around I think about I was about 21 22
years old you know I started realizing
you know a lot of things that you know
especially being married at a very young
age I mean I was 19 my wife was 16 when
we got married man so I mean you know
we've yeah we've been married 17 years
man so um it was right around that time
where I broke down to my wife you know
and I had to I had to tell her I mean
your wife I mean it's like I expressed
to a lot of people you there's no way
you could be a a a Divine Champion a
leader in life if you can't even lead
your home and so I expressed that like I
had to lead my home and so in order for
me to start leading my home I had to
express to my wife like yo this has
happened to me I want you to know like
this is what happened to me and my wife
started weeping you know and I started
weeping because I needed to let go I
needed to let go of these demons that
was sitting inside me this hatred this
malice that was sitting inside me this
this corruption that was sitting inside
me and let it out and expose it for what
it was and boy did I feel 100 straight I
felt like wow like somebody had just
tooken like a big old bag off my
shoulders you know what I'm saying
that's how I felt I felt just revived
you know and I just kept going forward
after that and and now I'm not I'm not
embarrassed nor am I ashamed of
expressing it in fact when I go and do
speaking engagements sometimes I'll
bring it up you know that that you know
what just because I was sexually abused
for a number of years doesn't mean that
I need to stay a part of the statistics
and Go whoo is me whoo is me give me the
pharmaceutical give me the treatments
nah nuh man I'm sorry but you know what
you are A Champion I am a leader I'm the
surgent and I'm I'm I'm the I I say the
mind surgent and the heart surgent
because when I look at those characters
man the heart and mind surgeon are the
people with power they spent hours and
hours on hours on mastering their trait
and so that's what they stay in they
stay in that field they don't go on to
become Structural Engineers or anything
like that but I look at that and say man
you know what all those all those trials
and tribulations all those those
circumstances in life they've helped to
push me onto greater and better things
and helping other people change their
life in the process wow you know I have
a song called uh spared and um the
lyrics I'll send it to you afterwards
but
that were that went to school for social
uh social work etc and they came at
things at a different angle they came at
coaching Etc at a different angle it it
didn't feel right to
me you know you're not going to motivate
kids they're like so let's have a powwow
how are we going to get the kids from
you know gangs off the
street you know they didn't know first
thing the first thing as a youth I could
tell you that there wasn't a lot of
black police in like black uh security
guards in the train stations and we
would have so much problems with those
security guards my group that I was
working with we lobbied them to have
more diversity so when you do that the
crime goes down but that that came from
my
mouth because I lived it right I was
living that I was getting stopped
everywhere I went even though I was
wearing a hoodie I got stopped right so
all I'm saying is that there's certain
people people that you want to listen to
because they've lived through
it right this this man is a husband a
father Mentor learner transformational
speaker entrepreneur sports coach
Progressive development coach and in
Inventor he's Jamaican man cuz he has
threee jobs I'm
joking uh was an individual with
learning disabilities and I come from
that I have dyslexia so I completely
understand
um came from a broken home single parent
with dementia and and reverse depression
and a product of foster care um boards a
boy's orphanage okay I've heard this man
speak so when he calls when when you
when you know there's old saying when
when the when the elders call you come
when I wake up 5:30 in the morning I see
his post and he says one thing there's
no sugar in my coffee we're not sugar
conies it y'all he's a nice guy but he
he packs a meane punch so I want you
guys to give it
up for Frank sagasta how's it going
Frank what's happening Ryan how you
doing well thank you so much for
inviting me to the hustle Zone man I
appreciate it it's a wonderful time to
be back on and uh to unleash man unleash
I'm like the heart surgeon the brain
surgent let's keep going
y so how did you think about that uh
that introduction because I honestly
feel that you know it I wanted to to
just say that is that there's certain
people in the community you want to
listen to people that have had that
experience and and I believe you're that
person you're that person that really
can provide guidance because you've been
through a lot just like myself and a few
others that we know yeah you know yeah I
I I definitely have been through a lot
in the years that I've been on this
Earth and I know that you know in time
time goes Time Heals everything and
that's exactly what's happened in my
transformation you know when made when I
started making my transformation in 2010
um all these different things started
happening they started evolving but I
mean before that you had another you had
almost about 12 years where I was
sitting around elders and just learning
and absorbing and just listening to
Great uh you know principles great uh
teachings and so I just applied them to
my
life so people are going to hate me if I
don't ask this
question the F before I before I go into
the question I just want remind people
cuz people ask me what's the hustle Zone
well if you didn't see all the spam then
um the hustle zone is uh we we are an
entrepreneurial group it's for
entrepreneurs by entrepreneurs we
develop content uh to motivate each
other there's not enough content in the
world that would get us sick and tired
of of of seeing you know we just love
motivational because you know before I
doing the hustle Zone I uh you know my
Facebook feed was really negative but
the more friends I that were in my
circle I just realized that I'm always
pumped up I'm always happy and uh so the
H the hustle zone is about that so we
pretty much tell the story rather than
the glory we want to highlight the glory
but we tell the story because we want to
humanize the
entrepreneur uh we want to humanize the
entrepreneur to show people that you can
change your H your your you could change
your life all you got to do is change
your habits us entrepreneurs have
specific habits that we follow to keep
us going right health so that's what the
hustle zone is all about so if you want
to get on please uh add yourself to the
group um add yourself to the Facebook
page Etc so um
Frank the one question I have to ask
what is your
story my story my story starts from you
know a broken home as I said you know a
single parent my story is basically the
potential of My Success and what I mean
by that is everything that I've gone
through is actually what's going to make
me you know I use my pain all my trials
and
tribulations strugg all the
circumstances that I have gone through
in life to push me on to great things
you know and I I always use I always use
the analogy of climbing up a mountain as
a as a Advocate hiker um that I I I am
still um and as an advocate you know
Mountain bik a cyclist a mountain biker
um you know there's two types of bikers
you have you have a roadie then you have
out in the the um the mountain biker and
um you know looking at that man all the
trials that you see all the trails that
you see and you go through they all lead
to somewhere you know and for me
climbing so many different mountains
within the State of Arizona it's always
been to accomplish A View to always see
a view and to always achieve that view
and no matter how big the mountain was I
wanted to definitely do it and I always
just had was so passionate about it and
so that's the same thing for Success you
know this the mountain is huge it's
Everest I I I I expressed to a lot of
people it's Everest so all the things
that I went through in life from being
sexually abused as a child to being with
the mother that suffered from uh
dementia and Alzheimer's and and severe
depression um it just pushed me and
fueled me and then taken from my
mother's hands and placed into uh into
foster care was just more ammunition you
know i' I've heard people say you know I
wish I had a better mother I mean I I
was in a boy's orphanage where I heard
that constantly man I wish my mother was
I wish I would have had a better mother
I wish I had a better father but the
reality is when you look back on this
I'm thankful for the mother that I did I
barely knew I'm thankful for that
because if it wasn't for that person I
would not be the person I am today right
so I'm gifted I'm absolutely gifted so
that's my story man I you know of course
there's more that we could dive into but
we'd be here for months man well this is
all like we got a whole hour so this is
all you my and um so we're going to
we're going to like today we're going to
get deep you know as as deep as you as
you want me to go um but you know and I
can identify you know I I I had a
turbulent relationship with my mother
and um been through a lot and um you
know and it's so like mothers are so
important in the happiness of you know
young young boys you know in the
happiness the out look mothers play an
important role and when they're not
there you know it it just seems that
when you don't feel like you have your
parents there you have to almost develop
a a
resiliency and you have to take on
things that
yourselves and um and I can identify
with that so can you elaborate your
relationship with your
mother yeah my mother I I you know as I
said I could I could definitely dive in
my my mom had as I said she had some
health complications some mental
complications um you know today I know a
whole lot more than what I did back then
but I can say that you know um it was
hard for my mom to take in this young
child cuz I mean I was the baby out of
five brothers one sister all much older
than me like my old my youngest the
second to the youngest brother is 40 I'm
sorry 52 whoa here you know what I'm
saying so there's a big huge age
difference there I mean there basically
old enough to be my father right so um
my mother was suffering with with so
many different Health complications that
it was hard for her to raise me so I
mean the conversation that normal kid
would have with their parent I didn't
have that opportunity there were times
where I come home um from being out in
the streets and she'd be staring off in
in a dark in a dark corner just in space
in in severe depression or she would
forget to feed me and I would just get a
tortilla and a hot dog and put it over
the stove and turn it put in a tortilla
and just eat for the night that's what I
would have or I'd go to the neighbor's
house and I'd eat dinner with them you
know what I'm saying these are these are
the things that I had so when it comes
to conversation I didn't have much
strong conversation with my mom I didn't
have a a true um a true foundation of
relationship with my mother now I wish I
would have you know but I mean
ultimately like when I had to make the
decision to pull the plug on my mom U
when she was when she was passing away I
was 21 years old but I mean you know
that was the hardest decision I ever
made in my life because here's a woman
that brought me into life and as much as
she was on that deathbed and she was
dying all I could do was sing hymns to
her and just talk to her in her ear and
I don't know if she could really
subconsciously hear me but I did it
anyways so I mean that was probably the
biggest opportunity for me to have a
strong conversation with my mother and
always remember that but all the other
stuff that I remember like my mom didn't
know how she didn't know what to do when
I when I when she found out I was being
sexually abused for number of years she
didn't know how to take it she didn't
she didn't do anything you know so I
mean that's kind of where I was with my
mom you know it was it was it was a
there was there was there was no real
true uh kinship that you see with other
kids and their parents I didn't have
that how how did you feel during that
time because I mean you know when me
raising my
son you know I I didn't really have a
great childhood when I was raising my
son a lot of flashbacks I would have a
lot of flashbacks of what you know
happened in my past like I was happy
during that time I thought MH but when
you look back you you get sad and you're
like wow
that all happened you know what I mean
and it hits
you um when did it hit you that you know
to the magnitude of what had all trans
transpired so for me um you know when I
started when I started writing my book
um you you owe yourselves um there's
some parts in there where it's it's a
self-help book and it's only 65 pages
but it's a it's 65 it was directed
towards writing my my story of my life
and it was redefine what you think is
possible was the first title and then it
started going off into more of a
self-help book and I started putting
points in there for an advocate reader
for a bibl file person that reads A Lot
would definitely start seeing different
key points in there uh you know and um
in in that book I write a little bit
about my mom's um you know her her her
her her disease and I almost began to
rep man because it really hit me but
going back like I would
say right
around 11 years old I was about 11 years
old I was homeless um I was running away
from foster home to foster home as a
runaway I was sleeping um the first
place I slept was an abandoned house in
Barstow California and uh and I cried
myself to sleep I was 11 years old and I
was hungry um and I I remember crying
myself to sleep because I was missing my
mother and you know and now that was
probably the worst time I ever felt at
that at that point beside taking you
know taking the last uh little bit of
air from my mother and saying that I
love her and that I'll always miss her
and I wish she could have seen her
grandkids but because she never got the
opportunity to see her grandkids grow up
and to see what they're like but that
was probably a hard time right there man
is meming um trying to recall those
memories and now for me today like I can
vividly literally vividly remember every
single memory from the time of when I
was 5 years years old playing with GI
Joe's out in the street or throwing
rocks at trucks at diesels just for them
to chase me I mean I remember these
things because I vividly played them
over and over again in my memory that I
would memorize them I would never let
them go because memories last forever
and I could share them with my kids you
know so yeah that was that was the time
that it hurt the most man I was sleeping
in an abandoned building and and and
wishing I was with my mom what what led
you to homelessness like what was the
what was the um yeah so uh you know
going back to that man I was uh I was
taken from my mom about 9 10 10ish and
uh I was I was placed into my my
sister's care and uh after 1992 we had a
big earthquake in California and at that
time my niece which is only a year older
than me um we took my sister's car and
so everything was pointed at me at that
time you know I was the bad kid I was
The Bad Seed right because Frankie was
just bad he was just running away and
doing bad things um and so ultim wasad
SE right she just said take them I mean
I I'll never forget those words like she
said take them you know I can't hand
them like like I was like an animal and
it took me a long time to forgive her
but I did forgive her I've never
forgotten but i' I've forgiven her but
then man then is when I started
realizing that you know uh that time
when I was taken away and placing the
foster care every home that I went to I
ran away from I didn't stay at a foster
home it wasn't until I became I was I
was grabbed by San bino County Sheriff's
and placed into a all boys orphanage
where I couldn't run and the reason why
I couldn't run is because they had
24hour night shifts so the so the the
counselors were always on staff so there
was no way you were running out of the
house plus they locked the doors every
single night so I mean you had a
counselor in the living room you had a
counselor in the back room and they were
watching you guys like a hawk so I mean
that's how it was wow so you how did you
feel then because I know myself I would
have been like how the hell did I get
out of here you know what I mean how
were you what were you going through
during that time 1994 is when I was
placed in uh into the orphanage and uh
you know I was I was really like I was I
got remember I was I was I was homeless
before then because I was running away
from fost room to Foster room but in 19
and right around 94 when they picked
when sanino County Sheriffs picked me up
they gave me two choices one I could go
to a a milary camp or I could go to a
boy orphanage and so um I took the boys
orphanage I had you know that was the
best outlet so when I got there I was
very new knew no knew nobody in the home
there's eight boys there knew nobody um
and uh I was vulnerable man it's like
it's you know it's it's like it's like
taking an individual out of his you know
out of his is is is his ordinary area
and then placing him into you know
almost like a almost like a prison
because you've never been there you know
know what those people were like you
have no idea what their psychological
backgrounds are and that's exactly what
it was so I was I stayed in my room for
about three days man I went uh you know
I didn't start school right away I
started school a week later um but I
stayed in my room most of the time and
just sat there and just looked outside
and um would go sit on the couch and was
really depressed and um I would just sit
by myself and and wouldn't talk to much
people I barely eat and it it was like
that for a long time man until I started
getting into sports and the counselor
started mentoring me and and kind of
planting that seed of of of greatness
and and motivating me to to play sports
and so that's kind of what started
turning things around for me in my
life it it's funny that you say that you
know start instilling greatness because
I say that in the beginning of the video
every single time is that you know you
know I had a few you know few mentors
that came into my life and they said you
know you're destined for greatness and I
didn't believe that you know I honestly
thought I was going to be Tupac and um
you know I thought I was going to be a
gangster I thought I was going to be one
of the biggest gangsters and you know it
was funny is that um there were police
that were you know the police keep
profiles right and my mentor was saying
is like you know Ryan could have went
the other direction thank God you guys
saved him because he was smart out of
all the the guys he was hanging out with
that guy was smart he he would have done
gotten to that next Next Level and they
were surprised that my mentor was able
to to to reach me and the reason why he
reached me first thing he said is like I
knew Michael Jackson I was like oh okay
damn I'm a 50 degree black belt I'm like
okay I want to learn through you because
those were the things that I liked and
he used music because I was into music
and stuff still into music but you know
but he said you know Ryan he's from
Chicago you know I had this this
American accent never heard this accent
before you know was like Ryan
you are going to be great you're going
to be something one of these days I can
see it in you and whether he was
smoking something or just puffing
smoke I took it in I ate it up and I got
me to that next level and
so
when what did they what did your
counselor say to you to make you believe
that there is a future for you
play Like A
Champion
today so what happened is the director
that that that built and structurally
formatted
engineered um this boy's orphanage took
me under his wing and today he's he he's
on the council um and he was a staff
member for the mayor in San bino
California and he always used to tell me
that Frankie Be A Champion Frankie Be A
Champion he always used to tell me that
and one of the counselors there actually
my mentor uh in life my family he
graduated from the University of Notre
Dame and so his way of giving back was
donating his time he went to play with
the Los Angeles Rams but his time it was
about donating his time to the orphanage
and he became full-time and he devoted
so much time into me he became family
and and today I still call him family
like I'll call from Once one every at
least once a month I'll call him if not
every other month but I I still make
strong contact because out of every
every kid that was in that orphanage I'm
the only one I'm the only one out of all
the boys that ever come through there
and I can't even tell you how many kids
had come through there but I was the
only one to
graduate with a with a high school
diploma barely graduate but I mean I
graduated and then graduate from the
boys orphanage with full honors and for
after 5 years of service in there and
committed almost 125 rules that we had
to live by and you know and chores so I
mean um I put in the work I put in the
work being in there and and and he
always used to tell me that and today
when I still talk to him he says Frankie
I still want you to be a champion
Frankie I still want you to be a
champion so that always that always sat
well it always it always sat on my heart
and on the table of my mind that I never
wanted to break that so in everything I
did I always worked diligently and
consistently at being a champion and
even when I got into coaching at a young
age it was all about instilling
Championship material Championship uh
you know Vibrance in into each child
that I was coaching you know and all it
did was surround me with with different
coaches and a point where I was actually
going to to California New Mex or uh
Phoenix Arizona and up in the northern
the northern mountains to be around
coaches go to coaching clinics and it
was it was just a an alumni of NFL and
NCAA coaches it still goes on today it's
called o OD and it's offense defense and
it's it's an alumni it's it's one of the
first Contact sports in America um that
has been that's been around for 40 no
I'm I'm sorry going back 50 years now
it's been around and uh you have a lot
of superstars that come out and devote
time to it so I mean that's all that it
did was start building that iny that
champion that champion attitude that
champion you know uh Zeal to be to be a
champion to be a leader you know so
that's kind of what I that's what kind
of what what really instilled a lot in
me now uh when it came to
because and and I mean that's a hell of
a journey you know and you know abuse
was also part of your your your journey
MH and I mean you know I I I can say
that I've been you know in in an abusive
situation um in my past with my
mom and it was just a turbulent
relationship that I had uh and I'm
probably going to be write I'm not
writing a book but I'd be one of these
days when people interview me I'll
probably talk about it because I I
normally talk about it I'm not not not
afraid to talk about that stuff um it's
just really hard for my my sisters and
it's really hard for my family to hear
because nobody wants to to see the truth
because honestly I was looked upon as
the guy like no I I let me tell you this
okay my I was born out of wedlock and
with a dad that I never met I met him
last year in November in
2015 La I met him for the first time
and I was not liked by my mom you know
and I wasn't liked by you know everyone
knew the truth but I didn't and and I
was treated
differently and that abusive
relationship really affect Ed me um to
you know and I was always trying to to
find something to to I I always wanted
attention maybe that's reason why I
promote so much but you know I always
wanted people to be like hey you know
look at me but I always felt like people
looked looked down on me I didn't feel
that way how did you feel you know
because I mean first when you when you
are abused in any way whether it's
physical sexual or what have you um how
do you you feel like it's your fault and
I I spent like nearly 30 years of my
life believing that I had to
prove to people rather it was the people
that had to prove to me because I was a
child you know what I
mean right well you know for for for me
it was like the it was it was almost
like a um it was attention I mean
ultimately I mean I didn't get attention
at home because I had no father I had no
structural father at all and then my
mother was barely there from time to
time when she was there you know what I
mean because of her disease um so she
was there uh my siblings they would pop
in once in a blue moon so I mean it was
basically the neighborhood kids growing
up and the man across street they used
to sexually abuse me I mean and it went
on for years you know what I'm saying
and how it made me feel was I felt I
felt love like that you know I didn't
know if that was right or wrong I didn't
know back then you know I was I was a
young I was a young Morey but I'm saying
like that's that's you know looking back
on it like when I was when I was in my
teens I used to think like man I can't
believe people do that like you know I
was I was I was I had so much hatred so
much anger um just I mean I was full of
just malice man straight up malice and
uh that's why a lot of the things that
were happening in my life were problems
I was creating problems for myself
because I had so much built in me
against this man and I never could
forgive him for for years for years I
couldn't forgive him in fact I wanted
death on him and uh that's how bad it
was it was just eating me alive you know
and and in fact it turned me you doing
drugs and drinking and being around you
know that kind of life you know so I
mean yeah it made it made it made a a
mess out of things it made an absolute
mess out of things when did you realize
that you know the situation that
happened to you wasn't your fault oh man
I would say right around I think about I
was about 21 22 years old you know I
started realizing you know a lot of
things that you know especially being
married at a very young age I mean I was
19 my wife was 16 when we got married
man so I mean you know we've yeah we've
been married 17 years man so um it was
right around that time where I broke
down to my wife you know and I had to I
had to tell her I mean your wife I mean
it's like I expressed to a lot of people
you there's no way you could be a a a
Divine champion a leader in life if you
can't even lead your home and so I
expressed that like I had to lead my
home and so in order for me to start
leading my home I had to express to my
wife like yo this has happened to me I
want you to know like this is what
happened to me and my wife started
weeping you know and I started weeping
because I needed to let go I needed to
let go of these demons that were sitting
inside me this hatred this malice that
was sitting inside me this this
corruption that was sitting inside me
and let it out and expose it for what it
was and boy did I feel 100 straight I
felt like wow like some of just tooking
like a big old bag off my shoulders you
know what I'm saying that's how I felt I
felt just revived you know and I just
kept going forward after that and and
now I'm not I'm not embarrassed nor am I
ashamed of expressing it in fact when I
go and do speaking engagements sometimes
I'll bring it up you know that that you
know what just because I was sexually
abused for a number of years doesn't
mean that I need to stay a part of the
statistics and Go whoo is me whoo is me
give me the pharmaceutical give me the
treatments nah nuh man I'm sorry but you
know what you are A Champion I am a
leader I'm the surgent and I'm I'm I'm
the I I say the Mind surgeon and the
heart surgent because when I look at
those characters man the heart and mind
surgeon are the people with power
they've spent hours and hours on hours
on mastering their trait and so that's
what they stay in they stay in that
field they don't go on to become
structural engineer or anything like
that but I look at that and say man you
know what all those all those trials and
tribulations all those those
circumstances in life they've helped to
push me onto greater and better things
and helping other people change their
life in the process wow you know I have
a song called uh spared and um the
lyrics I'll send it to you afterwards
but please the the this the lyrics are
um God spared my life because I knew
that she didn't want me
God spared my life because of
circumstance weren't wanted something
like that but God knew I was
important God knew I was important
because God only tests those who he
wants to lead that's right and you know
I felt alone and I feared being alone
for the longest time I feared being
alone by myself being an introvert and
my mom didn't let me uh you know leave
the house I was like would be barricaded
in my house um and I couldn't didn't
have a social life or whatever
and I could look at that as the GL glass
of being half empty or I can look at it
as being half full and it was half full
because I developed all these
talents but I also developed you know
being alone it really gave me the
ability that I really you can't have
five leaders that's right you can you
know there's only a few like most
mes was a prophet but he was one he was
one we
David Jesus grew up without their
fathers right and I consider myself
Joshua you know I followed Moses I've
met Moses and I feel like I was Joshua
because you know I went and spied
everybody I was young and I got to learn
I I got so many mentors I still don't
have my high school education but I went
and I have all these mentors that taught
me what what I need to know and I proved
everybody wrong right and so did you you
know you took all those experiences and
now you've made yourself a beautiful
life and every day you're you are from
what I see you're an advocate of you
know of everything that you
preach there's no sugar in your coffee
so tell me about the the the all the
blessings that had come from being you
know again pressure you know diamonds
yeah go through a lot of pressure you
know I going you know right right before
graduation I was able to sit down I I've
had a I I mean I had a wonderful time
even in the in the boy orphan is when
everybody was going and you know on on
the weekends a lot of the boys would go
with their families and it was kind of
strange because I never understood like
why do your fam come pick you
up and you're still here like I never
understood that you know it wasn't until
later on in life that I figured it out
that they were in there not not because
they were forced to be in there like me
they were in there because their parents
couldn't handle them and so they put
they placed them in there voluntarily
that's what they call it they call it
volunteer but I was just like wow and I
would sometimes be there for a week
while they went on vacation with their
families and stuff and then they would
come back and I was just like you know
so um shortly after that man when I got
back into Arizona and I and I got
married and and started seeing the real
Blessings by marriage in itself because
one of the things I expressed with a lot
of people being married 17 years at a
young very young age is I had to learn
patience I had to learn patience I had
to learn that this was going to be my
spouse for the rest of my life this was
going to be my partner for the rest of
my life and despite all the things that
we went through in our young early
marriage you know we had to get through
it and you know I I always thank God for
the times that we went through with the
trials and tribulations that we went
through as a young marriage because it
just made our our our our our devotion
our Unity so much stronger right and I
share that with a lot of people like
when I consult people in marriage like
sometimes I no sugar and M Coffee I just
say it man I give it to them absolutely
straight um and it's because of my
experience because I got 17 years in the
game of being married because I've I've
I've cheated on my because I left my
wife I know what that's like but the
blessings that come from that from those
as as you said earlier sometimes God
will take you through some trials and
tribulation and that's so true he does
take you through wants to test you and
see where you're at and it's like you
know I expressed the other day I say you
know I'd rather I want to be the catfish
in the
ocean because everybody is out to get
the fish and what fish do they always
pull out first the catfish I'll be the
catfish you know what I'm saying I'll be
the I'll be the ocean and what I'm
saying by that is I want I want you know
now I look back and I and there's times
where I definitely say you know what God
test me let me show you that I'm
faithful let me continue to show you on
Fai because I've been doing it for seven
years strong and I thank you so much cuz
I am so much appreciative of everything
he's bestowed upon me I have three
beautiful kids that they're very healthy
they play sports they're they're readers
now they're Learners um you know they
don't get into trouble and and you know
I'm just I'm blessed by that I'm blessed
by my marriage I'm blessed by my faith
I'm blessed that I'm getting the
opportunity you know to to like last
year be a reader a learner because in
all the years like a College Dropout
here I am a College Dropout barely got
through college barely got through high
school but yet even with the learning
disability I've been able to finish 55
books last year and this year I'll
finish 65 books and and and and and use
and use that information it's like you
know I heard one person say you read all
those books what did you get I got
knowledge I got information informative
stuff that helps me grow today and it's
helping my family grow because I'm
taking the information and I'm applying
it to my life and then I'm organizing it
and then I'm applying action to it you
know so you know I express said like the
blessings man have been building our
business coaching Beyond started in 200
well at the end of 2015 it started
working and working and working and
getting the momentum going for coaching
Beyond in 2016 2017 we go we went public
and so now it's now it's more of
official and uh we're just going forward
with that you know and then with the
invention um you know just you know what
I woke up one morning God gave me an
opportunity to draw something up and I'm
not an artist um no more am I an
engineer by by Trey but I got an idea
and uh I put it in paper and send it
over and got it stamped and approved and
now it's on the last process and and so
yeah you know I just that that's a
blessing to me you know the blessing is
definitely waking up every single
morning with the lungs of inspiration
and setting feet on God's green earth
with enthusiasm brushing my teeth with
with with optimism and showering down
with determination for every single day
you know so I mean this is the blessing
this is the absolute blessing what's
your relationship like with your kids oh
man so you got to remember I used to be
their coach I was their sports coach you
know I was their PE coach so I mean it
was different man because I mean not too
many Fathers and Sons can have that
relationship so it was always you know
um it was kind of hard it was hard for
me to distance myself as being that
coach because I've always been that
coach since I got out of high school
I've always mentored kids and and
started coaching peeee football but for
me and my kids it's more today I got my
oldest is 16 Isaac is 16 Andrew is 14
there's more of a a matured level of you
know of respect for each other and
there's at times I I I do have to scold
him but I mean for the most part man you
know what I mean they're 16 years old
and they're and they're very bright
they're colorful they're you know
they're they're I was just looking at
some pictures today I was going through
one of my junk drawers and I found some
some older pictures and I was just like
man why can't they be this small again
you know because I mean I mean when they
were small like that man we used to go
outside and play Tonka toys man like I
had a garden I had a lush Garden we go
out there and play with a big old Tonka
trucks man and we get dirty you know
what I'm saying like that was the that
you today today is much different today
is like you know my son would be like
Dad you want to watch a movie dad you
want to go to the park dad you
want m game but I mean like that's the
relationship we have today dad guess
what uh what's name uh what's that guy's
name Chance the Rapper just came out
with a new a new CD Dad can we get that
let's get it you know I'm a big I'm a
big Chance the Rapper uh you know fan
and my kids are real big so I mean yeah
that we we we definitely revolve around
a lot more around Sports we revolve
around around our faith uh we revolve
around you know doing things as a family
and so that's kind of where we're at man
yeah yeah uh we got we got some comments
in the uh we got a lot of comments today
um why I know because Frankie's in the
house uh so uh Wade says you are all
here for a reason and our parents are
just the vessels that allow us to come
to the world um to do God's work and you
are living um and you are living the
unfoldings I learned our parents are not
supposed to stick around or like or like
us it's not easy to understand first but
the parents are suffering from some
unspoken issues and we became the point
point of focus of their issues or
ignored you are not the issue they are
um you're not you are important and look
you know I I I I want to say though
um uh that just sparked the thought it's
that there's there's there's a power
that we all have and it's the power of
forgiveness right because sometimes you
know I could blame my mom for everything
happened but you know she was 26 she was
26 when I when like you know like it it
just we had turbulent relationship just
she just didn't like me as a child right
it just didn't it didn't work out um but
she was young so when you look back in
being a a a young woman that's a single
mother making minimum wage I can
understand where she's coming from and I
can take those negative moments and I
can turn them into positive because I
really invest in my son I'm a good
parent you know so I don't want to say
my mom had a problem or she will you
know I don't want to look at her in that
light but I think that you know some
people see the Spectrum but not everyone
is supposed to otherwise I wouldn't be
here if everyone knew the answers I
wouldn't be doing what I do I wouldn't
be you know you know some people will
reach that certain Pinnacle so you know
do you believe the same thing like what
what is your relationship with the power
of
forgiveness so I I I believe you know
what you should always you should always
come to the point where you forget but
going back going back to his question
you know your your parents didn't know
this and it's never been taught in the
school system it was never taught by
their our grandparents or anybody but
you know we have one of the most
essential powers that a lot of people
don't really take into consideration and
that's changing one thought over another
but aside from that is you know
everybody's to say oh you're a product
of your environment you're a product of
your environment well hold up wait now
because some you got to remember you you
make your environment so if your
environment is bad it's because you made
a choice to be in that environment so I
mean ultimately I look back on and say
you know what to guys that there was a
lot of times where I made a lot of
mistakes but I made them like it was my
choice so the environment that I was
staying when I was living in that
abandoned house in Boston California is
because I put myself in that environment
so I was the creator of my environment
so yeah I'm a product of my environment
because I created it and so with with
going back to the forgiveness I had to
forgive myself and it's like that
self-esteem you have to you know for me
I had to forgive myself for the things
that I put myself through in order to
grow into the leader in order to grow
into the champion you know what I'm
saying so um you have to forgive you
have to forgive yourself my parents you
know for my mom in in her health
condition absolutely I've forgiven her
you know I'll never forget those
memories as I said I played them over
and over again in my mind that way I
would never forget them because I wasn't
with my mom for a very long time so
those those imaginations all those all
those things that I can remember they
always will paint her her face in my
mind and I'll never forget her face you
know what I'm saying so I I don't have
many pictures of my mom the few pictures
that I do have um you know they they're
stored away but I mean I've already
memorized where my mom was sitting when
I was a kid when I used to come home I
remember my mom like when she used to
have the Jo Witnesses come over to our
house I remember where she used to sit
and where she used to keep the te stuff
cuz I used to be the kid to go get the
tea stuff you could make tea for people
the elders that come over like I
remember those things but I've played
them over and over again my mind that
way I can memorize them but forgiveness
is key man you have to forgive yourself
in order to move to the next level to
the next stage that's that Progressive
development Progressive development is
in stages it's in stages it's like going
upstairs so what do you what do you say
to cuz you you're around a lot of Youth
what do you say to the youth that um
because there are some youth that just
believe that you can't reach them they
see coach coach looks you know like a
nice guy he looks you know clean cut you
know you can't help me what do you know
what do you know about me you know what
I mean like you ain't about that life
you don't know what I'm talking about
like um you know now like I used to go
to um like when I started working I used
to wear a suit everywhere because I
thought wearing a suit was everything
you know I thought when I'm rich I'm
going to wear a suit all the time so I
would eat wearing in a suit go to bed
wearing a suit you know I thought it was
just everything so I go to school with
the suit and then people like you're MC
you ain't you ain't an MC you don't know
what you're talking about until I start
speaking then they like ah okay I get it
I get it I get it but um what do you say
to youth that feel that they don't need
you they figured it out on their
own I usually bring a mirror with me and
uh on my mirror um my on my mirror
actually has the very top it says
winners win losers lose and then there's
a gap just enough for your face to go in
there and you look in I'm serious you
look in the mirror and then down at the
bottom it says if it doesn't challenge
you it won't change you and it's written
on the mirror now I did this on purpose
because I needed that two years ago and
I drew that on there and so I needed
that but every time that I got upset or
I got frustrated I would looking there
and say you know what you're going to be
a champion today watch me I can I will I
must and I just apply that to my to my
to my attitude and to my life and so for
kids that I see that I say you know what
you got to look in the mirror because
you're fighting your worst enemy this is
the person this is the person you're
fighting you know what I'm saying so
when you say you want to get to that
next level when you say you want to get
out of this environment and you keep on
going back to that environment it's
because of that choice the number the
one of the most powerful things in this
world is choice and so when you sit
there and you make those choices you
will the one that is in stuck in that
environment so until you face that man
in the mirror like Michael Jackson
said me and him actually share the same
birthday so I was just like you know
when I found that out when I was a kid
man I was just loved him even more man
but that's a that's a straight song like
you are the man in the mirror you face
that person and you know it's and and
saying that that's also building that
self-esteem because that your
self-esteem you know your self-esteem is
that looking in the mirror knowing if
you're heal if you're healthy you're
happy you're excited you're enthusiastic
about the person you see then you know
you're destined for greatness but if
there's some things that are definitely
not not in congruent or not not cohesive
to what you really want to attain then
yeah there's some
pain so we got a commercial uh and then
we're going to be back uh to finish off
this meeting this was awesome I think
this was a great we're going to have to
definitely get to back on the show um
and uh to talk about some other topics
but uh uh we're going to head to
Commercial and we'll get her to our our
next line of question questions
here and if you could put yourself on
mute a web design company in Calgary is
taking the concept of helping others to
a whole new level and as Robin Crawford
reports it was an Okanagan man who
inspired them to use their Tech skills
to help people with disabilities
it gives me great pleasure to introduce
to you Michael D Haynes a motivational
speaker an entrepreneur and a
businessman Michael Haynes is doing it
all and I absolutely love it it's the
best job I've ever had in the beginning
Haynes admits that he didn't know how to
get his customer service Consulting
business off the ground and then he met
Ryan Perez with bowai creative for every
website that we sell we donate uh free
websites to entrepreneurs with
disabilities the Calgary based company
builds websites for businesses Haynes
knew he needed a website to promote
himself and Perez knew he had the tools
to help we were always talking about
working um um in the in or doing
something for the disability for the for
people with disabilities um but we
didn't know what we were going to do and
I thought that this was a great time to
um to do something and and so we
invented this whole initiative like
pretty much around Michael bow tie
creative built and maintains an entire
website for hannes free of charge he um
put my ideas into
action and that made my my
job so much easier it's an initiative
that the four-person company is proud of
it's especially close to pre's heart
because he himself has dyslexia I paved
my own path and that's why this this
this project means so much to me because
I want to help other people create their
paths bow tii creative is now helping
other people with mental and physical
challenges build websites across North
America all because of Michael Haynes
he's a great guy and it's fantastic
working with him and I can't wait to see
what happens next for him if you know um
anyone that has a mental or physical
disability that wants to be an
entrepreneur or you know needs to needs
help to get started in the right
direction definitely check out our
website haes hopes with the kind of
support offered by Perez and his team
more people will find the confidence to
reach their goals I have a challenge you
have a challenge there not a person
alive without a
challenge
I my challenge is more pronounced that
than yours Robin Crawford Global News
Colona okay and we're
back so
um so
Frank what's up man what does that say
on your shirt it says cin it's my it's
my talent it's my talent man and what
does that mean cousin means continuous
continuous Improvement it was by a
Japanese philosopher and businessman and
uh you know he he just it just inspired
me in
2015 and 2016 I put it into my talent
and uh been working just day and night
over it uh 365 days most people that
know me they know that I wake up last
year I started at 3:00 in the morning
this year it's at 2:30 um but I that's
continuous Improvement is you know
improving yourself and getting the best
out of the best um for the best you know
so I mean that's kind of pretty much
what it is and uh it's it's part of my
it's part of my
life what is your favorite thing to do
during the time where you're
recharging oh besides Sports yeah yeah
so uh today well i' I've actually taken
off Sports and put a lot more time and
thought into my business and uh
Consulting individuals and and and
really spending more time my community I
do I'm starting to now change my my
um I guess our our level of where we're
at with our business and it's like a
8020 so I have 20% will be given to uh
paid uh paid clients and then 80% will
be donated to schools Boys and Girls
Club into the community so more
Community Service uh will be done you
know for free of charge and stuff like
that um but you know what do I do on my
spirit time my Sundays are my days of
charge recharge Rebo re re rebooting the
mind and the body so there's no
electronics there's no there's none of
that um you know we spend it around
family and uh that's pretty much it man
that's that's my free time but other
than that I would say finding finding uh
an informative book that can definitely
bring something to my life um is pretty
much my my that's my that's my outlet
you know today um and it is for for some
of my family members too in this house
so awesome um so are you are you late
are you um do you come late or are you
usually on time uh I'm I'm on time I'm
all about time management um very I'm
very uh I'm very adamant about time
management as one of the earliest things
that I learned in college was about
being you know uh time time orientated
um and so I'm very I'm a big Advocate
about being on time I I time is
everything because time you can't get
back okay if you were to change your
career what would it
be uh if I could change my career um it
would probably
be it would probably still be an
education an education yeah yeah because
you seem like a teacher I feel like you
were my teacher back in the days you
just have that Vibe you know what I mean
like you seem like a teacher um what
what would you have said to your younger
self if you could if you go back in time
what would you tell that little boy I
would uh I would tell the individual I
had a teacher uh one of my one of my
first grade second grade teacher her
name was Mrs booty and I would I would
definitely tell myself to pay close
attention to what she was saying when
she said to be a listener and to really
put more thought into everything that I
did um you know I would I would
definitely hone in on that you know
versus walking away way and you know
being defiant you know in the situation
of where I was at I definitely would
because I think things would have been a
little different you know I probably
would have graduated with my Master's
Degree already I probably would have
graduated at the top of my class at high
school but you know what that doesn't
that doesn't separate me from who I am
today because you know what I what I
went through actually defined and helped
me to build build this person I am today
and so uh I'm thankful for that but yeah
I definitely I would definitely speak to
that person softly and say listen in
hone in on on what is being said what
makes you
mad
ignorance what makes you
happy ah what makes me
happy it's a good one what makes me
happy seeing people succeed in something
MH what's your favorite
dish
woo I say I I like enchiladas man I'm
big on enchiladas I love enchiladas oh
man don't tell me right now I've been
eating this like I don't know what I'm
eating all this this food to make me
lose weight and stuff like enchiladas I
could I okay we got switch that topic
right now I'm getting hungry I could I'm
just salivating right now um right right
yeah so we got to we're going to end
this uh conversation Frank I really
enjoy the convers I I wanted you on for
a long time
uh because I know we were going to hit
it off and I knew that we were going to
get deep because I mean we've been on
shows together in the past um however I
know you're a deep thinker I remember
seeing you when you went to philadel or
I think it was Philadelphia right yeah
and I'm a I'm a really intuitive person
and I'm an observer and I just watched
you in the background just sitting there
thinking you know and processing and I'm
like you
know it like wasn't that you were out of
your element it was just that you were
you know you were starting to you you
were you were just aware of your
situation and you were really going
through the motion and I'm like you know
I really want to sit down and talk with
this guy because this guy's a deep
thinker he's a he's a guy that you know
really has a good judgment of character
he knows what's up um and you know so
that's why I've wanted you on this show
for a long time because I know that we
can CU I like to get deep sometimes you
you know what I mean I like to get into
cuz you know like there's some there's
written and mind you I love all stories
but I like the story and always I love
it that's what the hustle Zone's all
about it's you guys shaped this this
brand you and uh a few others really
shaped this brand because it's about
that grit that keeps you going because
you realize it doesn't matter whether
it's dealing with bills or no bills
dealing with abuse or no abuse you still
have to go through those challenges so I
want to thank you so much from the
bottom of my heart for for coming into
the uh the hustle Zone Frank and um so
before you leave there's we got a ritual
so I'm going to do a call and response
and I think you know what that's all
about um so I'm going to say welcome to
the and you say and hustles on you got
to scream it out and if you don't scream
it out I'm gonna get you to do it again
until we get it get it right okay
so welcome to the hustle Z hustle Z baby
thank you so much uh Frank and uh so uh
I uh thank you for coming in and if you
don't mind putting yourself on mute for
a few minutes and then and then we'll be
done so
folks oh he hung
up uh yeah so so so folks this was an
amazing hustle Zone if you guys are not
following us on Twitter um
um I'm on Twitter now find me on Twitter
if you're not following our page uh if
you're not didn't add yourself to the
group you're not you're missing out on a
community of
entrepreneurs that um that will help
inspire you like every day I'm inspired
by the people that I'm around you know I
don't build this brand around me I build
it around the entrepreneur you know um
I've been you know
like now he could click the wrong button
says um but you know it's about you so
if you guys want to help develop content
for the hustle own magazine please hit
me up um create videos we'll brand it
we'll we'll put it out there um you know
cuz it's a community I love the
community aspect it's not about Ryan pz
h no it's it's about the community so I
want to thank you guys all for coming in
and if you guys want to get into that
fitness challenge I'm telling you um you
guys want to join um the hust and s
fitness challenge and uh special shout
out to Dave body U our social media
manager for sharing out those posts and
um and yeah thank you guys again um if
you guys want to book the hustle Zone
like the page book now um I'm not going
to chase after you um and there's some
people that don't want to click that
link you know a few people in mind and
um you know and honestly if you you
don't want to conform you don't want to
go through the steps that everyone else
has to take I see like I've had a lot of
success people on this show and they all
go through the steps so you know you're
no no one's an exception you know we all
have to put in that work so you know
please fill out that form and get
yourself in if you're interested in
being a part of the show we're not
chasing uh because it's you know if you
want people to hear your story and
sometimes I'll approach you um but if I
don't get a chance make sure you call me
CU I would love to hear your story I
love to hear stories they're all it's
amazing to me so thank you guys so much
and uh see you next
time we got some
[Music]
commercials we must always ask ourselves
this one question to be able to bring
forth growth and expansion and change in
our
operation that one question is this what
can I be able to do better more or
different we should be able to
comfortably and
confidently ask this question to the
people that we are leading in our lives
and around us and our organizations
wherever it
is the reality is is that by definition
insanity is doing the same thing over
and over again and expecting a different
result and we know this the sad thing is
is that a lot of people are going
through that and they're beating their
head against the wall and wondering why
nothing will change change I challenge
you ask this question to yourself what
can I do better more or
different style baby